<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?><RECIPES>
<RECIPE>
 <NAME>034 - Witterlig en saison</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>All Grain</TYPE>
 <BREWER>Dan</BREWER>
 <ASST_BREWER></ASST_BREWER>
 <BATCH_SIZE>25.0000000</BATCH_SIZE>
 <BOIL_SIZE>31.5833333</BOIL_SIZE>
 <BOIL_TIME>90.0000000</BOIL_TIME>
 <EFFICIENCY>75.0000000</EFFICIENCY>
 <HOPS>
<HOP>
 <NAME>Hallertau Magnum</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
 <ALPHA>13.8000000</ALPHA>
 <AMOUNT>0.0152065</AMOUNT>
 <USE>Boil</USE>
 <TIME>60.0000000</TIME>
 <NOTES>German Hallertauer hybrid, widely used in Germany. Extremely appropriate for early boil additions.
Used for: German ales and lagers, bitters, IPAs, pilsners, pale ales, stouts.
Aroma: somewhat unnoticeable aroma; stable spicy flavor
Substitutes: Hallertau Taurus, Columbus, Nugget
Storage: Excellent (80%-85% AA after 6 months at 20 C)
12-14% AA / 4.5-5.5% Beta</NOTES>
 <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
 <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
 <BETA>6.5000000</BETA>
 <HSI>17.5000000</HSI>
 <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>15.21 g</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
 <INVENTORY>0.00 g</INVENTORY>
 <DISPLAY_TIME>60.0 min</DISPLAY_TIME>
</HOP>
<HOP>
 <NAME>Saaz</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <ORIGIN>U.S.</ORIGIN>
 <ALPHA>4.3000000</ALPHA>
 <AMOUNT>0.0333819</AMOUNT>
 <USE>Boil</USE>
 <TIME>5.0000000</TIME>
 <NOTES>This traditional variety from the Czech Republic is grown on a limited basis in the U.S. A classic noble aroma that is famously used in Pilsners.
Used for: Bohemian-style beers, Continental lagers, Wheats, Pilsener lagers, Ales, Pilsners
Aroma: Seasoned herbal character
Substitiutions: Czech Saaz, Polish Lublin, Sterling
Storage: Poor
2-6% AA / 3-4.5% Beta</NOTES>
 <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
 <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
 <BETA>3.7500000</BETA>
 <HSI>50.0000000</HSI>
 <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>33.38 g</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
 <INVENTORY>0.00 g</INVENTORY>
 <DISPLAY_TIME>5.0 min</DISPLAY_TIME>
</HOP>
<HOP>
 <NAME>Saaz</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <ORIGIN>U.S.</ORIGIN>
 <ALPHA>4.3000000</ALPHA>
 <AMOUNT>0.0140000</AMOUNT>
 <USE>Boil</USE>
 <TIME>0.0000000</TIME>
 <NOTES>This traditional variety from the Czech Republic is grown on a limited basis in the U.S. A classic noble aroma that is famously used in Pilsners.
Used for: Bohemian-style beers, Continental lagers, Wheats, Pilsener lagers, Ales, Pilsners
Aroma: Seasoned herbal character
Substitiutions: Czech Saaz, Polish Lublin, Sterling
Storage: Poor
2-6% AA / 3-4.5% Beta</NOTES>
 <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
 <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
 <BETA>3.7500000</BETA>
 <HSI>50.0000000</HSI>
 <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>14.00 g</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
 <INVENTORY>0.00 g</INVENTORY>
 <DISPLAY_TIME>0.0 min</DISPLAY_TIME>
</HOP>
</HOPS>

 <FERMENTABLES>
<FERMENTABLE>
 <NAME>CH&#194;TEAU PILSEN 2RS</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
 <AMOUNT>4.3614815</AMOUNT>
 <YIELD>81.0000000</YIELD>
 <COLOR>2.9550000</COLOR>
 <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>FALSE</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
 <ORIGIN>Belgium</ORIGIN>
 <SUPPLIER>Castle Malting&#174;</SUPPLIER>
 <NOTES>Features: The lightest coloured Belgian malt. Produced from the finest European
malting barley varieties. Kilned at up to 80 - 85&#176;C.

Characteristics: The lightest in colour, this malt is well modified and can be easily
mashed with a single-temperature infusion. Our Ch&#226;teau Pilsen malt carries a
strong, sweet malt flavour and contains enough enzymatic power to be used as base
malt.

Usage: All beer types 

%:  Up to 100% of the mix

2.5 &#8211; 3.5 EBC (European Brewing Convention)
1.5 &#8211; 1.9&#176;L (Lovibond)

Moisture % 4.5

Extract (dry basis) % 81.0

Difference fine &#8211; coarse % 1.5-2.5

Wort colour EBC (&#176;L) 3.5 (1.9)

Post coloration EBC (&#176;L) 4.0 (2.1)- 6.0 (2.8)

Total Protein (dry malt) % 11.2

Soluble protein % 3.5-4.4

Kolbach Index % 35.0-45.0

Hartong 45&#176; % 34.0-43.0

Viscosity cp 1.6

Ph 5.6-6.0

Diastatic power WK 250

Friability % 81.0

Glassiness (whole grains) % 2.5

PDMS 5.0

NDMA ppb 2.5

Filtration normal

Saccharification time min 15

Clarity of wort clear


</NOTES>
 <COARSE_FINE_DIFF>2.0000000</COARSE_FINE_DIFF>
 <MOISTURE>4.5000000</MOISTURE>
 <DIASTATIC_POWER>250.0000000</DIASTATIC_POWER>
 <PROTEIN>11.2000000</PROTEIN>
 <MAX_IN_BATCH>100.0000000</MAX_IN_BATCH>
 <RECOMMEND_MASH>TRUE</RECOMMEND_MASH>
 <IBU_GAL_PER_LB>0.0000000</IBU_GAL_PER_LB>
 <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>4.36 kg</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
 <INVENTORY>0.00 kg</INVENTORY>
 <POTENTIAL>1.0372600</POTENTIAL>
 <DISPLAY_COLOR>3.0 EBC</DISPLAY_COLOR>
 <EXTRACT_SUBSTITUTE></EXTRACT_SUBSTITUTE>
</FERMENTABLE>
<FERMENTABLE>
 <NAME>CH&#194;TEAU ACID</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
 <AMOUNT>0.2725926</AMOUNT>
 <YIELD>74.0000000</YIELD>
 <COLOR>9.4560000</COLOR>
 <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>FALSE</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
 <ORIGIN>Belgium</ORIGIN>
 <SUPPLIER>Castle Malting&#174;</SUPPLIER>
 <NOTES>Features: It is an acidulated with lactobacilli barley malt which lowers the mash pH and is used when brewing with bicarbonate-rich water.

Characteristics: Ch&#226;teau Acid malt improves the performance of the hydrolytic enzymes and provides a better mash working. It also intensifies the fermentation by adjusting the pH level. Acid malt enhances a well-rounded taste in your beer and gives stability to its head.

Usage: Any ale or lager, wheat beers, light beers for optimizing the pH level.

6 &#8211; 13 EBC (European Brewing Convention)
2.8 &#8211;5.4&#176;L (Lovibond)

Moisture % 5.0 - 10.0
Extract (dry basis) - % 74
Wort color EBC(Lov.) 6 (2.8) - 13 (5.4)
Total protein % 9.5 - 11.5
pH - 5.0
Acidity - 40</NOTES>
 <COARSE_FINE_DIFF>0.0000000</COARSE_FINE_DIFF>
 <MOISTURE>7.5000000</MOISTURE>
 <DIASTATIC_POWER>0.0000000</DIASTATIC_POWER>
 <PROTEIN>10.5000000</PROTEIN>
 <MAX_IN_BATCH>5.0000000</MAX_IN_BATCH>
 <RECOMMEND_MASH>TRUE</RECOMMEND_MASH>
 <IBU_GAL_PER_LB>0.0000000</IBU_GAL_PER_LB>
 <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.27 kg</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
 <INVENTORY>0.00 kg</INVENTORY>
 <POTENTIAL>1.0340400</POTENTIAL>
 <DISPLAY_COLOR>9.5 EBC</DISPLAY_COLOR>
 <EXTRACT_SUBSTITUTE></EXTRACT_SUBSTITUTE>
</FERMENTABLE>
<FERMENTABLE>
 <NAME>CH&#194;TEAU MUNICH</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
 <AMOUNT>0.2725926</AMOUNT>
 <YIELD>80.0000000</YIELD>
 <COLOR>24.9993000</COLOR>
 <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>FALSE</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
 <ORIGIN>Belgium</ORIGIN>
 <SUPPLIER>Castle Malting&#174;</SUPPLIER>
 <NOTES>25 EBC (European Brewing Convention)

Features: Belgian specialty malt of M&#252;nich type. Kilned up to 100-105&#176;C.

Characteristics: Rich, golden malt. Provides a modest colour increase toward a nice,
golden-orange colour. Adds a pronounced grainy malty flavour to many beer styles
without affecting the foam stability and body. Is also used in small quantities in
combination with Ch&#226;teau Pilsen 2RS to produce light colour beers, improving the
malty flavour and giving the beer a richer colour. Enhances the taste of character
beers.

Usage: Pale ale, amber, brown, strong and dark beers, bocks

%: Up to 60% of the mix

Moisture % 4.5

Extract (dry basis) % 80.0

Wort colour EBC (&#176;L) 21.0 (8.4) 28.0 (11.1)

Total Protein (dry malt) % 11.5

Clarity of wort % clear

</NOTES>
 <COARSE_FINE_DIFF>2.0000000</COARSE_FINE_DIFF>
 <MOISTURE>4.5000000</MOISTURE>
 <DIASTATIC_POWER>100.0000000</DIASTATIC_POWER>
 <PROTEIN>11.5000000</PROTEIN>
 <MAX_IN_BATCH>60.0000000</MAX_IN_BATCH>
 <RECOMMEND_MASH>TRUE</RECOMMEND_MASH>
 <IBU_GAL_PER_LB>0.0000000</IBU_GAL_PER_LB>
 <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.27 kg</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
 <INVENTORY>0.00 kg</INVENTORY>
 <POTENTIAL>1.0368000</POTENTIAL>
 <DISPLAY_COLOR>25.0 EBC</DISPLAY_COLOR>
 <EXTRACT_SUBSTITUTE></EXTRACT_SUBSTITUTE>
</FERMENTABLE>
<FERMENTABLE>
 <NAME>CH&#194;TEAU WHEAT BLANC</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
 <AMOUNT>0.2725926</AMOUNT>
 <YIELD>83.0000000</YIELD>
 <COLOR>4.5310000</COLOR>
 <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>FALSE</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
 <ORIGIN>Belgium</ORIGIN>
 <SUPPLIER>Castle Malting&#174;</SUPPLIER>
 <NOTES>Features: Wheat malt. Kilned at up to 80 - 85&#176;C.

Characteristics: Enhances the peculiar taste of wheat beers. Ch&#226;teau Wheat Blanc malt is essential in making wheat beers but is also used in barley malt-based beers (3&#8211;5%) thanks to its protein level that gives the beer a fuller mouthfeel and enhanced head stability.

Usage: Wheat beers, white, light beers, beers with low or no alcohol. Recommended max. proportion: up to 30% of the mix.

3.5 &#8211;5.5 EBC (European Brewing Convention)
1.9 &#8211;2.6&#176;L (Lovibond)

Moisture % 5.5

Extract (dry basis) % 83.0

Wortcolour EBC (&#176;L) 5.5 (2.6)

Postcoloration EBC (&#176;L) 7.5 (3.4)

Total Protein (dry malt) % 14.0

Soluble protein % 4.5- 5.5

Viscosity
cp 1.9
pH 5.8-6.1</NOTES>
 <COARSE_FINE_DIFF>0.0000000</COARSE_FINE_DIFF>
 <MOISTURE>5.5000000</MOISTURE>
 <DIASTATIC_POWER>0.0000000</DIASTATIC_POWER>
 <PROTEIN>14.0000000</PROTEIN>
 <MAX_IN_BATCH>30.0000000</MAX_IN_BATCH>
 <RECOMMEND_MASH>TRUE</RECOMMEND_MASH>
 <IBU_GAL_PER_LB>0.0000000</IBU_GAL_PER_LB>
 <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.27 kg</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
 <INVENTORY>0.00 kg</INVENTORY>
 <POTENTIAL>1.0381800</POTENTIAL>
 <DISPLAY_COLOR>4.5 EBC</DISPLAY_COLOR>
 <EXTRACT_SUBSTITUTE></EXTRACT_SUBSTITUTE>
</FERMENTABLE>
<FERMENTABLE>
 <NAME>CH&#194;TEAU WHEAT CRYSTAL&#174;</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
 <AMOUNT>0.2725926</AMOUNT>
 <YIELD>78.0000000</YIELD>
 <COLOR>150.1140000</COLOR>
 <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>FALSE</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
 <ORIGIN>Belgium</ORIGIN>
 <SUPPLIER>Castle Malting&#174;</SUPPLIER>
 <NOTES>Features: Distinct Belgian aromatic wheat malt with special caramelization developed by Castle Malting&#174;. Particular germination process. Caramelized in several steps to develop unique aroma and flavour.

Characteristics: This caramel-copper coloured wheat malt provides a rich malt flavour and aroma to amber and dark lager beers. Compared to other traditional coloured malts, Ch&#226;teau Wheat Crystal&#174; has an even stronger diastatic power and imparts a smoother bitterness.

Usage: Aromatic and coloured beers. Perfect for any beer in which high profile wheat malt is required. Excellent choice for Belgian ales and German bock beer styles. Up to 20% of the mix.

150EBC (European Brewing Convention)
56.8&#176;L (Lovibond)

Moisture % 4.5

Extract (dry basis) % 78.0

pH 5.8

Wortcolour EBC (&#176;L) 142.0 (53.8)
                                    158.0 (59.8)</NOTES>
 <COARSE_FINE_DIFF>0.0000000</COARSE_FINE_DIFF>
 <MOISTURE>4.5000000</MOISTURE>
 <DIASTATIC_POWER>0.0000000</DIASTATIC_POWER>
 <PROTEIN>0.0000000</PROTEIN>
 <MAX_IN_BATCH>20.0000000</MAX_IN_BATCH>
 <RECOMMEND_MASH>TRUE</RECOMMEND_MASH>
 <IBU_GAL_PER_LB>0.0000000</IBU_GAL_PER_LB>
 <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.27 kg</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
 <INVENTORY>0.00 kg</INVENTORY>
 <POTENTIAL>1.0358800</POTENTIAL>
 <DISPLAY_COLOR>150.1 EBC</DISPLAY_COLOR>
 <EXTRACT_SUBSTITUTE></EXTRACT_SUBSTITUTE>
</FERMENTABLE>
</FERMENTABLES>

 <MISCS>
<MISC>
 <NAME>Whirlfloc Tablet</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Fining</TYPE>
 <USE>Boil</USE>
 <AMOUNT>0.500000</AMOUNT>
 <TIME>15.00</TIME>
 <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>FALSE</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
 <USE_FOR>Clarity</USE_FOR>
 <NOTES>Aids in clearing yeast and chill haze.  Easy to use tablet form.</NOTES>
 <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.50 Items</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
 <INVENTORY>0.00 Items</INVENTORY>
 <DISPLAY_TIME>15.0 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
 <BATCH_SIZE>18.93 l</BATCH_SIZE>
</MISC>
</MISCS>

 <YEASTS>
<YEAST>
 <NAME>Belgian Wit Ale</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Wheat</TYPE>
 <FORM>Liquid</FORM>
 <AMOUNT>0.0354884</AMOUNT>
 <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>FALSE</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
 <LABORATORY>White Labs</LABORATORY>
 <PRODUCT_ID>WLP400</PRODUCT_ID>
 <MIN_TEMPERATURE>19.4444444</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
 <MAX_TEMPERATURE>23.3333333</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
 <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
 <ATTENUATION>76.0000000</ATTENUATION>
 <NOTES>Phenolic and tart.  The original yeast used to produce Wit in Belgium.</NOTES>
 <BEST_FOR>Belgian Wit</BEST_FOR>
 <MAX_REUSE>5</MAX_REUSE>
 <TIMES_CULTURED>0</TIMES_CULTURED>
 <ADD_TO_SECONDARY>FALSE</ADD_TO_SECONDARY>
 <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>35.49 ml</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
 <DISP_MIN_TEMP>19.4 C</DISP_MIN_TEMP>
 <DISP_MAX_TEMP>23.3 C</DISP_MAX_TEMP>
 <INVENTORY>0.0 pkg</INVENTORY>
 <CULTURE_DATE>14/06/03</CULTURE_DATE>
</YEAST>
</YEASTS>

 
 <STYLE>
 <NAME>Saison</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <CATEGORY>Belgian and French Ale</CATEGORY>
 <CATEGORY_NUMBER>16</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
 <STYLE_LETTER>C</STYLE_LETTER>
 <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
 <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
 <OG_MIN>1.0480000</OG_MIN>
 <OG_MAX>1.0650000</OG_MAX>
 <FG_MIN>1.0020000</FG_MIN>
 <FG_MAX>1.0120000</FG_MAX>
 <IBU_MIN>20.0000000</IBU_MIN>
 <IBU_MAX>35.0000000</IBU_MAX>
 <COLOR_MIN>9.8500000</COLOR_MIN>
 <COLOR_MAX>27.5800000</COLOR_MAX>
 <CARB_MIN>2.3000000</CARB_MIN>
 <CARB_MAX>2.9000000</CARB_MAX>
 <ABV_MAX>7.0000000</ABV_MAX>
 <ABV_MIN>5.0000000</ABV_MIN>
 <NOTES>A refreshing, medium to strong fruity/spicy ale with a distinctive yellow-orange color, highly carbonated, well hopped, and dry with a quenching acidity. A seasonal summer style produced in Wallonia, the French-speaking part of Belgium. Originally brewed at the end of the cool season to last through the warmer months before refrigeration was common. It had to be sturdy enough to last for months but not too strong to be quenching and refreshing in the summer. It is now brewed year-round in tiny, artisanal breweries whose buildings reflect their origins as farmhouses. Varying strength examples exist (table beers of about 5% strength, typical export beers of about 6.5%, and stronger versions of 8%+). Strong versions (6.5%-9.5%) and darker versions (copper to dark brown/black) should be entered as Belgian Specialty Ales (16E). Sweetness decreases and spice, hop and sour character increases with strength. Herb and spice additions often reflect the indigenous varieties available at the brewery. High carbonation and extreme attenuation (85-95%) helps bring out the many flavors and to increase the perception of a dry finish. All of these beers share somewhat higher levels of acidity than other Belgian styles while the optional sour flavor is often a variable house character of a particular brewery.</NOTES>
 <PROFILE>Aroma: High fruitiness with low to moderate hop aroma and moderate to no herb, spice and alcohol aroma. Fruity esters dominate the aroma and are often reminiscent of citrus fruits such as oranges or lemons. A low to medium-high spicy or floral hop aroma is usually present. A moderate spice aroma (from actual spice additions and/or yeast-derived phenols) complements the other aromatics. When phenolics are present they tend to be peppery rather than clove-like. A low to moderate sourness or acidity may be present, but should not overwhelm other characteristics. Spice, hop and sour aromatics typically increase with the strength of the beer. Alcohols are soft, spicy and low in intensity, and should not be hot or solventy. The malt character is light. No diacetyl.
Appearance: Often a distinctive pale orange but may be golden or amber in color. There is no correlation between strength and color. Long-lasting, dense, rocky white to ivory head resulting in characteristic &#8220;Belgian lace&#8221; on the glass as it fades. Clarity is poor to good though haze is not unexpected in this type of unfiltered farmhouse beer. Effervescent.
Flavor: Combination of fruity and spicy flavors supported by a soft malt character, a low to moderate alcohol presence and tart sourness. Extremely high attenuation gives a characteristic dry finish. The fruitiness is frequently citrusy (orange- or lemon-like). The addition of one of more spices serve to add complexity, but shouldn&#8217;t dominate in the balance. Low peppery yeast-derived phenols may be present instead of or in addition to spice additions; phenols tend to be lower than in many other Belgian beers, and complement the bitterness. Hop flavor is low to moderate, and is generally spicy or earthy in character. Hop bitterness may be moderate to high, but should not overwhelm fruity esters, spices, and malt. Malt character is light but provides a sufficient background for the other flavors. A low to moderate tart sourness may be present, but should not overwhelm other flavors. Spices, hop bitterness and flavor, and sourness commonly increase with the strength of the beer while sweetness decreases. No hot alcohol or solventy character. High carbonation, moderately sulfate water, and high attenuation give a very dry finish with a long, bitter, sometimes spicy aftertaste. The perceived bitterness is often higher than the IBU level would suggest. No diacetyl.
Mouthfeel: Light to medium body. Alcohol level can be medium to medium-high, though the warming character is low to medium. No hot alcohol or solventy character. Very high carbonation with an effervescent quality. There is enough prickly acidity on the tongue to balance the very dry finish. A low to moderate tart character may be present but should be refreshing and not to the point of puckering.</PROFILE>
 <INGREDIENTS>Pilsner malt dominates the grist though a portion of Vienna and/or Munich malt contributes color and complexity. Sometimes contains other grains such as wheat and spelt. Adjuncts such as sugar and honey can also serve to add complexity and thin the body. Hop bitterness and flavor may be more noticeable than in many other Belgian styles. A saison is sometimes dry-hopped. Noble hops, Styrian or East Kent Goldings are commonly used. A wide variety of herbs and spices are often used to add complexity and uniqueness in the stronger versions, but should always meld well with the yeast and hop character. Varying degrees of acidity and/or sourness can be created by the use of gypsum, acidulated malt, a sour mash or Lactobacillus. Hard water, common to most of Wallonia, can accentuate the bitterness and dry finish.</INGREDIENTS>
 <EXAMPLES>Saison Dupont Vieille Provision; Fant&#244;me Saison D&#8217;Erez&#233;e - Printemps; Saison de Pipaix; Saison Regal; Saison Voisin; Lefebvre Saison 1900; Ellezelloise Saison 2000; Saison Silly; Southampton Saison; New Belgium Saison; Pizza Port SPF 45; Lost Abbey Red Barn Ale; Ommegang Hennepin</EXAMPLES>
 <DISPLAY_OG_MIN>1.048 SG</DISPLAY_OG_MIN>
 <DISPLAY_OG_MAX>1.065 SG</DISPLAY_OG_MAX>
 <DISPLAY_FG_MIN>1.002 SG</DISPLAY_FG_MIN>
 <DISPLAY_FG_MAX>1.012 SG</DISPLAY_FG_MAX>
 <DISPLAY_COLOR_MIN>9.8 EBC</DISPLAY_COLOR_MIN>
 <DISPLAY_COLOR_MAX>27.6 EBC</DISPLAY_COLOR_MAX>
 <OG_RANGE>1,048-1,065 SG</OG_RANGE>
 <FG_RANGE>1,002-1,012 SG</FG_RANGE>
 <IBU_RANGE>20,0-35,0 IBUs</IBU_RANGE>
 <CARB_RANGE>2,30-2,90 Vols</CARB_RANGE>
 <COLOR_RANGE>9,8-27,6 EBC</COLOR_RANGE>
 <ABV_RANGE>5,00-7,00 %</ABV_RANGE>
</STYLE>

 <EQUIPMENT>
 <NAME>Grainfather</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <BOIL_SIZE>31.5833333</BOIL_SIZE>
 <BATCH_SIZE>25.0000000</BATCH_SIZE>
 <TUN_VOLUME>30.0000000</TUN_VOLUME>
 <TUN_WEIGHT>2.9999981</TUN_WEIGHT>
 <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.1200000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
 <TOP_UP_WATER>0.0000000</TOP_UP_WATER>
 <TRUB_CHILLER_LOSS>1.0000000</TRUB_CHILLER_LOSS>
 <EVAP_RATE>9.4986807</EVAP_RATE>
 <BOIL_TIME>90.0000000</BOIL_TIME>
 <CALC_BOIL_VOLUME>TRUE</CALC_BOIL_VOLUME>
 <LAUTER_DEADSPACE>0.0000000</LAUTER_DEADSPACE>
 <TOP_UP_KETTLE>0.0000000</TOP_UP_KETTLE>
 <HOP_UTILIZATION>100.0000000</HOP_UTILIZATION>
 <COOLING_LOSS_PCT>4.0000000</COOLING_LOSS_PCT>
 <NOTES>Grainfather Profile for BeerSmith V2.3
Water to Grain ratio should be set at 2.7L/kg when selecting a mash profile
Default grain absorption should be changed in the Beersmith Advanced settings (tools-&#62;options-&#62;advanced). The default setting is 0.96 fl oz/oz. This will need to be changed to 0.7669 fl oz/oz (0.8 L/kg) to line up exactly with the Grainfather official calulations</NOTES>
 <DISPLAY_BOIL_SIZE>31.58 l</DISPLAY_BOIL_SIZE>
 <DISPLAY_BATCH_SIZE>25.00 l</DISPLAY_BATCH_SIZE>
 <DISPLAY_TUN_VOLUME>30.00 l</DISPLAY_TUN_VOLUME>
 <DISPLAY_TUN_WEIGHT>3.00 kg</DISPLAY_TUN_WEIGHT>
 <DISPLAY_TOP_UP_WATER>0.00 l</DISPLAY_TOP_UP_WATER>
 <DISPLAY_TRUB_CHILLER_LOSS>1.00 l</DISPLAY_TRUB_CHILLER_LOSS>
 <DISPLAY_LAUTER_DEADSPACE>0.00 l</DISPLAY_LAUTER_DEADSPACE>
 <DISPLAY_TOP_UP_KETTLE>0.00 l</DISPLAY_TOP_UP_KETTLE>
</EQUIPMENT>

 <MASH>
 <NAME>Saison</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <GRAIN_TEMP>23.0000000</GRAIN_TEMP>
 <TUN_TEMP>23.0000000</TUN_TEMP>
 <SPARGE_TEMP>76.0000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
 <PH>5.2000000</PH>
 <TUN_WEIGHT>105.8219040</TUN_WEIGHT>
 <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.1200000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
 <EQUIP_ADJUST>TRUE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
 <NOTES></NOTES>
 <DISPLAY_GRAIN_TEMP>23.0 C</DISPLAY_GRAIN_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_TUN_TEMP>23.0 C</DISPLAY_TUN_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_SPARGE_TEMP>76.0 C</DISPLAY_SPARGE_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_TUN_WEIGHT>3.00 kg</DISPLAY_TUN_WEIGHT>
<MASH_STEPS>
<MASH_STEP>
 <NAME>Mash In</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
 <INFUSE_AMOUNT>17.4459372</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
 <STEP_TIME>10.0000000</STEP_TIME>
 <STEP_TEMP>45.0000000</STEP_TEMP>
 <RAMP_TIME>0.0000000</RAMP_TIME>
 <END_TEMP>45.0000000</END_TEMP>
 <DESCRIPTION>Add 20,95 l of water at 47,6 C</DESCRIPTION>
 <WATER_GRAIN_RATIO>3,200 l/kg</WATER_GRAIN_RATIO>
 <DECOCTION_AMT>0.00 l</DECOCTION_AMT>
 <INFUSE_TEMP>47.6 C</INFUSE_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_STEP_TEMP>45.0 C</DISPLAY_STEP_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_INFUSE_AMT>20.95 l</DISPLAY_INFUSE_AMT>
</MASH_STEP>
<MASH_STEP>
 <NAME>Mash Step</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
 <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.0000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
 <STEP_TIME>10.0000000</STEP_TIME>
 <STEP_TEMP>53.0000000</STEP_TEMP>
 <RAMP_TIME>5.0000000</RAMP_TIME>
 <END_TEMP>53.0000000</END_TEMP>
 <DESCRIPTION>Heat to 53,0 C over 5 min</DESCRIPTION>
 <WATER_GRAIN_RATIO>3,842 l/kg</WATER_GRAIN_RATIO>
 <DECOCTION_AMT>0.00 l</DECOCTION_AMT>
 <INFUSE_TEMP>53.0 C</INFUSE_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_STEP_TEMP>53.0 C</DISPLAY_STEP_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_INFUSE_AMT>0.00 l</DISPLAY_INFUSE_AMT>
</MASH_STEP>
<MASH_STEP>
 <NAME>Mash Step</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
 <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.0000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
 <STEP_TIME>10.0000000</STEP_TIME>
 <STEP_TEMP>63.0000000</STEP_TEMP>
 <RAMP_TIME>5.0000000</RAMP_TIME>
 <END_TEMP>63.0000000</END_TEMP>
 <DESCRIPTION>Heat to 63,0 C over 5 min</DESCRIPTION>
 <WATER_GRAIN_RATIO>3,842 l/kg</WATER_GRAIN_RATIO>
 <DECOCTION_AMT>0.00 l</DECOCTION_AMT>
 <INFUSE_TEMP>63.0 C</INFUSE_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_STEP_TEMP>63.0 C</DISPLAY_STEP_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_INFUSE_AMT>0.00 l</DISPLAY_INFUSE_AMT>
</MASH_STEP>
<MASH_STEP>
 <NAME>Mash Step</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
 <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.0000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
 <STEP_TIME>10.0000000</STEP_TIME>
 <STEP_TEMP>68.0000000</STEP_TEMP>
 <RAMP_TIME>5.0000000</RAMP_TIME>
 <END_TEMP>68.0000000</END_TEMP>
 <DESCRIPTION>Heat to 68,0 C over 5 min</DESCRIPTION>
 <WATER_GRAIN_RATIO>3,842 l/kg</WATER_GRAIN_RATIO>
 <DECOCTION_AMT>0.00 l</DECOCTION_AMT>
 <INFUSE_TEMP>68.0 C</INFUSE_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_STEP_TEMP>68.0 C</DISPLAY_STEP_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_INFUSE_AMT>0.00 l</DISPLAY_INFUSE_AMT>
</MASH_STEP>
<MASH_STEP>
 <NAME>Mash Step</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
 <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.0000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
 <STEP_TIME>10.0000000</STEP_TIME>
 <STEP_TEMP>72.0000000</STEP_TEMP>
 <RAMP_TIME>5.0000000</RAMP_TIME>
 <END_TEMP>72.0000000</END_TEMP>
 <DESCRIPTION>Heat to 72,0 C over 5 min</DESCRIPTION>
 <WATER_GRAIN_RATIO>3,842 l/kg</WATER_GRAIN_RATIO>
 <DECOCTION_AMT>0.00 l</DECOCTION_AMT>
 <INFUSE_TEMP>72.0 C</INFUSE_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_STEP_TEMP>72.0 C</DISPLAY_STEP_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_INFUSE_AMT>0.00 l</DISPLAY_INFUSE_AMT>
</MASH_STEP>
<MASH_STEP>
 <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
 <VERSION>1</VERSION>
 <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
 <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.0000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
 <STEP_TIME>10.0000000</STEP_TIME>
 <STEP_TEMP>78.0000000</STEP_TEMP>
 <RAMP_TIME>5.0000000</RAMP_TIME>
 <END_TEMP>78.0000000</END_TEMP>
 <DESCRIPTION>Heat to 78,0 C over 5 min</DESCRIPTION>
 <WATER_GRAIN_RATIO>3,842 l/kg</WATER_GRAIN_RATIO>
 <DECOCTION_AMT>0.00 l</DECOCTION_AMT>
 <INFUSE_TEMP>78.0 C</INFUSE_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_STEP_TEMP>78.0 C</DISPLAY_STEP_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_INFUSE_AMT>0.00 l</DISPLAY_INFUSE_AMT>
</MASH_STEP>
</MASH_STEPS>

</MASH>

 <NOTES></NOTES>
 <TASTE_NOTES></TASTE_NOTES>
 <TASTE_RATING>30.0000000</TASTE_RATING>
 <OG>1.0504430</OG>
 <FG>1.0096472</FG>
 <CARBONATION>3.0000000</CARBONATION>
 <FERMENTATION_STAGES>2</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
 <PRIMARY_AGE>14.0000000</PRIMARY_AGE>
 <PRIMARY_TEMP>20.0000000</PRIMARY_TEMP>
 <SECONDARY_AGE>14.0000000</SECONDARY_AGE>
 <SECONDARY_TEMP>20.0000000</SECONDARY_TEMP>
 <TERTIARY_AGE>7.0000000</TERTIARY_AGE>
 <AGE>30.0000000</AGE>
 <AGE_TEMP>11.0000000</AGE_TEMP>
 <CARBONATION_USED>Bottle with 181,90 g Table Sugar</CARBONATION_USED>
 <FORCED_CARBONATION>TRUE</FORCED_CARBONATION>
 <PRIMING_SUGAR_NAME>Table Sugar</PRIMING_SUGAR_NAME>
 <PRIMING_SUGAR_EQUIV>0.9099181</PRIMING_SUGAR_EQUIV>
 <KEG_PRIMING_FACTOR>0.5000000</KEG_PRIMING_FACTOR>
 <CARBONATION_TEMP>21.1111111</CARBONATION_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_CARB_TEMP>21.1 C</DISPLAY_CARB_TEMP>
 <DATE>01/04/16</DATE>
 <EST_OG>1.051 SG</EST_OG>
 <EST_FG>1.013 SG</EST_FG>
 <EST_COLOR>14.7 EBC</EST_COLOR>
 <IBU>25.0 IBUs</IBU>
 <IBU_METHOD>Tinseth</IBU_METHOD>
 <EST_ABV>5.0 %</EST_ABV>
 <ABV>5.3 %</ABV>
 <ACTUAL_EFFICIENCY>74.8 %</ACTUAL_EFFICIENCY>
 <CALORIES>469.2 kcal/l</CALORIES>
 <DISPLAY_BATCH_SIZE>25.00 l</DISPLAY_BATCH_SIZE>
 <DISPLAY_BOIL_SIZE>31.58 l</DISPLAY_BOIL_SIZE>
 <DISPLAY_OG>1.050 SG</DISPLAY_OG>
 <DISPLAY_FG>1.010 SG</DISPLAY_FG>
 <DISPLAY_PRIMARY_TEMP>20.0 C</DISPLAY_PRIMARY_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_SECONDARY_TEMP>20.0 C</DISPLAY_SECONDARY_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_TERTIARY_TEMP>18.3 C</DISPLAY_TERTIARY_TEMP>
 <DISPLAY_AGE_TEMP>11.0 C</DISPLAY_AGE_TEMP>
</RECIPE>
</RECIPES>
